What is a function declaration, and why is it important?
什么是函数声明 为什么它很重要？
A function declaration has
函数声明有多个片段
multiple pieces and this is a little easier to look at in code.
这在代码中看起来更容易一些
Maybe let's look at your tests normalize function.
我们最好看看你的 tests normalize 函数
When you look at just the way the function is defined,
当你只看函数定义的方式时
there's the bool and then the tests normalize and the open paren and the close paren.
首先是这个布尔值 然后是 tests normalize 接着是左括号 右括号
And that bool says that it's going to return true or false.
这个布尔值表示它会返回 true 或 false
Very similar to Python,
与 Python 非常类似
you can return whatever you want,
你可以返回任何你想要的值
except in C++ you have to tell it the type you're going to return.
不过在 C++ 中 你必须告诉它你想要返回的类型
It has some advantages.
它有一些优势
For example in Python,
例如在 Python 中
if you accidentally returned just the row,
如果你不小心只是返回了行
instead of the whole grid, it wouldn't tell you,
却没有返回整个网格 Python 不会告诉你
you wouldn't know until it ran, and there was an error.
只有在语言运行时 你才知道出了错
Maybe three hours into what you were doing,
或许从你设置到发现错误已经过去三小时
it would suddenly get to a place in the code where there was a bug and you would now.
它会突然跳到代码中有 bug 的地方 你才能发现问题
But C++, it tells you right away,
但是 C++ 却会马上告诉你
you can't even compile if you didn't
如果你没有返回一些值 没有返回一些正确的值
return something and return something of the right variety.
你甚至无法编辑
Something I do in Python a lot is actually forget the return statement, entirely.
我在 Python 中经常犯的一个错误是 我会完全忘记返回语句
And then I am working with a none type object forever.
然后我就一直在处理一个无类型的对象
And that's actually can be a really hard bug to debug.
这实际上可能是一个非常难调试的 bug
So I can see how this might be valuable.
所以我很清楚函数声明的价值所在
Exactly.
没错
You're at least guaranteed that the parts fit together correctly.
你至少保证了这些零件正确地组装在一起
Not necessarily that they do what they're supposed to, but that they fit.
它们可能不能达成预期功能 不过确实可以互相匹配
Right, the Lego blocks go together,
没错 乐高积木自成一体
and that you didn't forget one.
你不会遗忘任何一块
Okay.
好的
It's so easy to forget the return or to return just the wrong thing,
忘记返回或返回错误的值经常发生
because you were thinking about something else.
因为你可能正在思考其他事情
Hopefully, C++ has a few safety checks for you.
幸好的是 C++ 具备安全检查功能 这会对你所有帮助